[{"question":"<p>Aliya keeps having a &quot;C&quot; grade in what subject?<\/p>","options":["Mathematics","Biology","Physics","Chemistry"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In the novel, Aliya sufferes &quot;body shaming&quot; from which of these charaters?<\/p>","options":["Zak","Her Biology teacher","Miss Salako","Aunty Molara"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Abdullahi, having written extensively over the years on politics, policy&nbsp; and development. &quot;Sweeet Sixteen was his&quot; ________________<\/p>","options":["Fifth book","First book","Third book","Second book"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Rebecca says all Muslim will go to hell because<\/p>","options":["they do not believe in Jesus","they marry more than one wife","they are violent","they hate people of other religions"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Which of the following was the concluding story hold by Aliya&#39;s father to solidify Aliya&#39;s Self-realization?<\/p>","options":["The Mahatma Gandhi story","His own childhood story","The Slave and the Captor story","The Hunter's story"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The Novel &quot;Sweet Sixteen&quot; is naratted in ______________<\/p>","options":["Second person narratives","First person narratives","Third person narratives","Second person subjected narratives"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Which of these character is opinionated that relationships comes with a lot of emotional issues one can bear?<\/p>","options":["Aliya's Father","Aliya's Biology teacher","Aliya's Mothers","Aliya's Friend"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What was Aliya&#39;s reason of not considering choosing a career as a doctor in the novel?<\/p>","options":["Because she hates the sight of blood","Because passing chemistry was difficult","Because of her health condition","She doesn't want to compete with her mother"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In which of the chapter, does Aliya&#39;s father thinks: &quot;Music is a universal language that speakes to the soul&quot;<\/p>","options":["Grandhi's test","Stereotype","Dating","Beauty"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>According to the novel, Aliya&#39;s Father favourites singer was ___________<\/p>","options":["Wizkid","Ali Farka Toure'","Fela Anikulapo","Tu-face"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>&quot;For their soul dwell in the house of tomorrow, which you cannot visit, not even in your dreams&quot; This excerpt by Kahild Gibran in the Novel means?<\/p>","options":["Parent should determine the Children's career","Parents will determine the success of their children in life","Parents should not determine their children's career","Parent should constantly have heart-felt discussion with their children"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Mr Bello meets his wife at\/in<\/p>","options":["his workplace","a hospital","a cafeteria","a bus"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Mr. Bello oinion about girls who bleach their skin is that they<\/p>","options":["need help","lack self-confidence","are bad influence to the younger generation","are products of westernization"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>&quot;Do you know any cardiologist, because my heart skips a beat every time i think of you&quot; The excerpt above is the content of the notes Aliya receives from ___________<\/p>","options":["Zak","Tokunbo Alabi","Bolaji","Akin"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In the novel, in which of these chapter reveals that &quot;a jealous mind is a distracted mind<\/p>","options":["Drive","The letter","Dating","work"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Bolaji Abdullahi&#39;s &quot;Sweet Sixteen&quot; is written in<\/p>","options":["first and third person narratives","omniscient point of view","first person narrative","dialogues"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>According to the Novel K.P.C is a social media language that means__________<\/p>","options":["keep places clean","keep party clothes","keep parent clueless","kind party care"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In the novel, Aliya&#39;s class mate that refers to himself as &quot;Kings of boy&quot; is __________<\/p>","options":["Akin","Tokunbo Alabi","Bobo","Bunmi"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Which of these character in the novel often bully&#39;s her in school<\/p>","options":["Grace","Tokunbo","Bunmi","Bisi"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>According to the novel, which of these society has &quot;Fat-farms&quot;, where girls were force-fed to fatten them in the novel<\/p>","options":["Niger","Mauritania","Ibadan","Ghana"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What Mr. Bello detest most are not saying your prayers on time and<\/p>","options":["arguing blindly","telling lies","shouting while talking","being disobedient"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Who is Mr. Bello&#39;s favourite musician<\/p>","options":["Fela","Adekunle Gold","Ebenezer Obey","Ali Farka Toure"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In the novel, Akin, fondly calls himself _________<\/p>","options":["King of girls","Gold medalist","King of boys","Eye of the eagle"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The girl who is caught having sex in school has not only suffered humilation but also lost her<\/p>","options":["parents","virginity","boyfriend","self-respect"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>According to Mr. Bello, people bully others because<\/p>","options":["they are anti-social","it is a way of easing stress","they feel inferior to those they bully","they are sadists"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>According to the novel, which of these character is described as a clear gold medalist<\/p>","options":["Grace","Akin","Tokunbo Alabi","Aliya"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The novel &quot;Sweet Sixteen&quot; is published by ___________<\/p>","options":["Masobe Books","Lantern Printing Press","Jamb Printing Press","Molara Wood Printing Press"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Whenever Aiya&#39;s mum stops being angry, she<\/p>","options":["starts praising her daughter","sings around the house","comes home early from work","takes the family out for a treat"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>&quot;Beauty is nothing, but character is needed&quot;. This sentence means<\/p>","options":["physical beauty is useless in the society","a beautiful person ignores character","having a good character is the most beautiful thing","character attracts while beauty sustains good relationships with people"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In the novel, the casual but deliberately planned drive around the city between Aliya and her father was because ____________<\/p>","options":["Aliya's mother had inform him that Aliya has seen her first menstrual period","none of the above","Aliya's mother had informed him that Aliya now has a boyfriend","Aliya's teacher had informed him that she was moody"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Birthdays are not celebrated in Aliya&#39;s family because<\/p>","options":["it reminds them they are closer to the grave","Aliya's father dislikes parties","it is not considered a major achievement","it brings back bad memories"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>According to the novel, how did Aliya got to know that at age 16 one is no longer a child?<\/p>","options":["from the 16 page letter from her dad","from a book titled","from a movie at the cinema","from the book titled"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The letter titled &#39;Letter to my Daughter&#39; has the same title as a book written by<\/p>","options":["Operah Winfrey","Chimamanda Adichie","Magaret Thatcher","Maya Angelou"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Apart from the malian singer, who was Mr. Bello&#39;s favourite, whose music does he likes too?<\/p>","options":["Fela's music","King Sunny Ade's Music","Ali Farka toure music","Tiwa savage's music"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>According to the navel, Aliya is informed that the casual drive. She had with her father was deliberately arranged by him through ____________<\/p>","options":["none of the above","their discussion at her school garden","the sixteen page letter written to her","the discussion in her bedroom"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What is the main message of the story about the hunter?<\/p>","options":["averaging others may be right or wrong, depending on the circumstances","parents should pass across their wealth of knowledge to their children and the children should do same when they grow up","it is wrong to revenge wrongdoings","it is good to always prepare for difficult situations"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>As at the time Aliya was born, her father was working as a _______________<\/p>","options":["Pilot","Journalist","Teacher","Banker"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Being generous, according to Mr. Bello means<\/p>","options":["going out of your way to make others happy","giving people everything you have","meeting people's need every time they ask","smiling always"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In the novel, Mr Bello define&#39;s a &quot;dump girl&quot; as ____________<\/p>","options":["a girl who collects valentine gift from a boy","a girl who accept other peope's definition of beauty","A girl who has sex with a boy to prove she loves him","a girl who cheats during exam"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The letter Aliya&#39;s father writes to her on her birthday has how many pages?<\/p>","options":["16 + 1 extra page","16 pages","12 pages","16 + 2 extra pages her mum added"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Aliya doesn&#39;t do well in her chemistry exams because<\/p>","options":["she doesn't read enough","she usually has exam fever","time is never enough to answer the questions","her teacher deliberately fails her"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What is Bobo&#39;s real name?<\/p>","options":["Bobola","Adebowale","Tokunbo","Bobo"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What is Aliya&#39;s father&#39;s reaction to the gift she recieves from Bobo?<\/p>","options":["he asks her to return it","he advises her that the gift doesn't necessarily mean he truly loves her","he tells her she has to reciprocate by giving him a gift too","he asks to speak with Bobo"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>A dumb girl, according to Bolaji Abdullahi&#39;s &#39;Sweet Sixteen&#39; is all of following except one<\/p>","options":["who doesn't do well in exams","who doesn't know when she is being manipulated","who misbehaves","who has sex with a boy to prove she loves him"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Aliya suffers from what kind of illness?<\/p>","options":["Asthma","Leukemia","Sickle cell anaemia","hepatitis"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Aliya&#39;s father tries to teach Aliya chess because<\/p>","options":["it will improve her social skills","it is a game that can be played alone","it will help reduce her anxiety","it will make her think strategically"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Aliya gets all these letters for her 16th birthday except<\/p>","options":["a letter","a digital camera","a birthday card","a teddy bear"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The birth of Aliya to Mr. Bello makes him<\/p>","options":["appreciates his wife more","long for more children","take life more seriously","remember is childhood"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>&quot;Watching those things is like dragging filth into your beautiful room&quot;. One of these filth which is referred to is<\/p>","options":["vulgarity","homosexuality","disobedience","racism"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What\/who inspired Aliya to become a Lawyer?<\/p>","options":["her father","a friend","an incident where someone is wrongly accused","John Grisham's books"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What is the Gandhi test?<\/p>","options":["you may strive to be like them, but seek not to make them like you","to strive to seek, to find and not to yield","you can tell that what you are doing is good or bad if you want other people to know about it or not","can we rise above our persona feelings and sentiments in particular situations or not"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Aliya&#39;s mother comes from<\/p>","options":["a polygamous family","a rich background","a poor background","a middle class family"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In book, is Gandhi a present?<\/p>","options":["yes","no","maybe","I don't know"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What does HAK mean in the book?<\/p>","options":["hands and knees","hold and knock","hugs and kisses","hate and knead"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The girl who is caught having sex in school has not only suffered humiliation but also lost her<\/p>","options":["parents","virginity","self-respect","boyfriend"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>A set of idea that people have above what someone or something is especially an idea that is wrong is known as<\/p>","options":["stereotypes","lies","disbelief","hatred"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The slave who was tortured eventually<\/p>","options":["gained his freedom by running away","died of his wounds","nursed his torturer back to health","died during the shipwreck"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>According to Mr. Bello, we can actually influence and change people in a significant way by<\/p>","options":["tell them what to do","reacting to them differently","avoiding them completely","imitating them"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Aliya called Latifat by her teacher because<\/p>","options":["he wants to body shame her","he doesn't know her name","it is her nickname","Latifat is also a Muslim name"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Making negative comments about somebody&#39;s weight or size is known as<\/p>","options":["body shaming","body shameing","body shading","body shadeing"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Gandhi&#39;s quote &quot;nobody can hurt me without my permision&quot; means<\/p>","options":["we should permit people to hurt us","we can control how other people behave towards us","we should be able to control how others make us feel","people should always seek permission before they hurt us"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In which of these Nigerian tribes is it a norm for women to put on weight in order to attract suitors for marriage?<\/p>","options":["Mauritania","Efik","Ibibio","Urhobo"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Mr. Bello opinion about girls who bleach their skin is that they;<\/p>","options":["need help","are products of westernization","are bad influence to the younger generation","lack self-confidence"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The setting of the book &#39;Sweet Sixteen&#39; by Bolaji Abdullahi is<\/p>","options":["Nigeria","Mali","Mauritania","Ghana"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What does Aliya want to donate to the school clinic?<\/p>","options":["books","the Nebuliser","writing materials","sporting equipment"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>One of the dominant narrative techniques employed in the book is<\/p>","options":["allusion","metaphor","flashback","foreshadowing"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Aliya is going to be what prefect in her school?<\/p>","options":["Head Girl","Health Prefect","Assembly Prefect","School Prefect"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What is Bobo&#39;s real name?<\/p>","options":["Bobola","Adebowale","Tokunbo","Bobo"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>How does Aliya show stereotype?<\/p>","options":["she dislikes Rebecca and Bunmi","she says Christians think their religion is better than Islamic religion","she hates her chemistry teacher","she feels the other girls in her class are dumb"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In Bolaji Abdullahi&#39;s &#39;Sweet Sixteen&#39;, Kahlil Gibran is a<\/p>","options":["poet","songwriter","dramatist","musician"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>At some point in the book, why doesn&#39;t Aliya want to be the grown-up girl she always want to be anymore?<\/p>","options":["she thinks her father is dead","she doen't feel anything when she is 16","she likes to remain a child","she thinks her father is dead"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>One of Mr. Bello&#39;s friend referred to in the book is<\/p>","options":["Mr. Shittu","The Principal","Dr. Folarin","Mrs. Rebeccah"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Who is the protagonist in the book sweet sixteen?<\/p>","options":["Aliya","Mr. Bello","Bobo","Tokunbo"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The birth of Aliya to Mr. Bello makes him<\/p>","options":["appreciates his wife more","long for more children","take life more seriously","remember is childhood"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>&quot;Watching those things is like dragging filth into your beautiful room&quot;. One of these filth which is referred to is<\/p>","options":["vulgarity","homosexuality","disobedience","racism"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>At some point in her life, Aliya contemplates all of these future ambitions except<\/p>","options":["Fashion designing","Law","Music","Accounting"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What\/who inspired Aliya to become a Lawyer?<\/p>","options":["her father","a friend","an incident where someone is wrongly accused","John Grisham's books"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What is the Gandhi test?<\/p>","options":["you may strive to be like them, but seek not to make them like you","to strive to seek, to find and not to yield","you can tell that what you are doing is good or bad if you want other people to know about it or not","can we rise above our persona feelings and sentiments in particular situations or not"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Aliya&#39;s mother comes from<\/p>","options":["a polygamous family","a rich background","a poor background","a middle class family"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In book, is Gandhi a present?<\/p>","options":["yes","no","maybe","I don't know"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What does HAK mean in the book?<\/p>","options":["hands and knees","hold and knock","hugs and kisses","hate and knead"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The girl who is caught having sex in school has not only suffered humiliation but also lost her<\/p>","options":["parents","virginity","self-respect","boyfriend"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>A set of idea that people have above what someone or something is especially an idea that is wrong is known as<\/p>","options":["stereotypes","lies","disbelief","hatred"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The slave who was tortured eventually<\/p>","options":["gained his freedom by running away","died of his wounds","nursed his torturer back to health","died during the shipwreck"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>According to Mr. Bello, we can actually influence and change people in a significant way by<\/p>","options":["tell them what to do","reacting to them differently","avoiding them completely","imitating them"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Aliya called Latifat by her teacher because<\/p>","options":["he wants to body shame her","he doesn't know her name","it is her nickname","Latifat is also a Muslim name"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Making negative comments about somebody&#39;s weight or size is known as<\/p>","options":["body shaming","body shameing","body shading","body shadeing"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Gandhi&#39;s quote &quot;nobody can hurt me without my permision&quot; means<\/p>","options":["we should permit people to hurt us","we can control how other people behave towards us","we should be able to control how others make us feel","people should always seek permission before they hurt us"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In which of these Nigerian tribes is it a norm for women to put on weight in order to attract suitors for marriage?<\/p>","options":["Mauritania","Efik","Ibibio","Urhobo"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Mr. Bello opinion about girls who bleach their skin is that they;<\/p>","options":["need help","are products of westernization","are bad influence to the younger generation","lack self-confidence"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>The setting of the book &#39;Sweet Sixteen&#39; by Bolaji Abdullahi is<\/p>","options":["Nigeria","Mali","Mauritania","Ghana"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>What does Aliya want to donate to the school clinic?<\/p>","options":["books","the Nebuliser","writing materials","sporting equipment"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>One of the dominant narrative techniques employed in the book is<\/p>","options":["allusion","metaphor","flashback","foreshadowing"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Aliya is going to be what prefect in her school?<\/p>","options":["Head Girl","Health Prefect","Assembly Prefect","School Prefect"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Bunmi usually tuant Aliya because<\/p>","options":["she is fat","she is a Muslim","her parents don't give her enough freedom","she is more brilliant"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>How does Aliya show stereotype?<\/p>","options":["she dislikes Rebecca and Bunmi","she says Christians think their religion is better than Islamic religion","she hates her chemistry teacher","she feels the other girls in her class are dumb"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>In Bolaji Abdullahi&#39;s &#39;Sweet Sixteen&#39;, Kahlil Gibran is a<\/p>","options":["poet","songwriter","dramatist","musician"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>At some point in the book, why doesn&#39;t Aliya want to be the grown-up girl she always want to be anymore?<\/p>","options":["she thinks her father is dead","she doen't feel anything when she is 16","she likes to remain a child","she thinks her father is dead"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>One of Mr. Bello&#39;s friend referred to in the book is<\/p>","options":["Mr. Shittu","The Principal","Dr. Folarin","Mrs. Rebeccah"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2019"},{"question":"<p>Who is the protagonist in the book sweet sixteen?<\/p>","options":["Aliya","Mr. Bello","Bobo","Tokunbo"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2019"}]